hello today we're gonna talk about the
Haymarket Riot Chicago huge industrial
city it's like the 1880s August bees
moved from Germany worked for German
socialist newspaper he's like alright
let's we need we need to we need better
to working conditions isn't that I'm
gonna big rally and for the McCormick
plant they mechanize the whole plant but
the workers that I haven't like no this
is our skillful this is what this is the
Union so they're on strike
August Spees is their Argos peas he goes
there he gives a speech he's like you
stick with your Union be solid you know
you just beat but you know be together
don't go crazy or nothing but just be
with your group but you know beat be
solid
said cops they're of course they got
cops there well she goes wrong some of
the striking workers they rush the gates
at the McCormick plant cops they shoot
they kill a couple of strikers species
us he sees us is it cause let's not do
this and a lot of fancy words
let's open the door in case that barf no
no I just fell out of the chair a little
bit if you like
I love laying on my floor too like don't
feel like you gotta get back good it's a
good floor the great hardwood floor yeah
he goes back he right the Reds of
protest to whatever happened the whole
thing is like get an eight-hour a
eight-hour workday okay just just get an
8 to 8 hour work day and it's just
undermining it this that like this is
what they're doing they're trying to
with us they're trying to force conflict
and just they I worked at click clack
clickety clack so they raise this whole
thing give it a headline make sure it
gets out there well the guy who gives it
a headline it just says for revenger
he's like no we don't stand for violence
but it's closed out revenge and we want
a I would like all when I got take
anymore it's already a labor we have
around we're gonna do a goddamn TV show
they're talking or and they're they're
speaking their minds on it even a
Harrison the mayor of Chicago shows up
like I'm here I'm not upset about this
they're speaking of mines it's cooled
what a blow but they're in our kids the
nuts are just doing what they're doing
and they're not saying anything terrible
on the mayor I said this is cool let him
go let him go I'm taking off one of the
guys is up there guys guys hey we're
getting--we're busting our asses he
invokes the guys that died the day
before it at the McCormick plant and
people are getting riled up so please
step in said all right nope nope we're
gonna we're gonna step in we need you to
disperse the name of Chicago Police
Department we need you to get going take
a hike you're done
this bomb comes hurling it nobody knows
where it came from nobody know who threw
the bomb bow on all Kaos Haymarket ride
shots shots go up eight people died
we're going yep ready we know Oh what
happens the next day it's martial law
that's what happens the next day it's
martial law they arrest eight people
including August peace
no no evidence no evidence that they
build bombs they arrest them all under
the guise of conspiracy bulls Spees was
like no I stand with these guys I
proclaim my innocence but I'm standing
with everybody so an ex editor of the
Chicago Tribune said don't hang them
these are the people that allow you to
be a millionaire business owner you want
to start a war with these people cuz
once these people decide to go you your
luck except the guy that got in at
martial infield the biggest
industrialist in Chicago at the time we
should agree with the labor leaders nope
I don't want to do it and will not
concede to these people he's dirty
long-haired filthy an anarchist
socialist garbage pieces of people
squash labor leaders squash it off hang
the bastards
we are so let's be honest let's be
honest let's be honest 3ci silences
powerful more so than your other stuff
the day will come
I'm watching it switched around and I'm
mad about it I got this you got this
my little fragrance candle for you index
[Music]
No and now we only work eight hours a
day eight hours a day
you